The Lord is a God of social justice.
That’s the message in many—maybe most—churches
and synagogues in America and the West today.
But here’s the problem: The Bible doesn’t
actually say that. It says (in Isaiah), “The
Lord is a God of justice公正.” You’ll find
a lot of references to justice in the Bible.
But you’ll never find it preceded被放置在前面的 by the
word “social.”
But you’re probably thinking, “What’s
the difference? Isn’t God the God of justice
and social justice?” Well, not if He’s
consistent一致的. You see, God cannot be the God
of justice and social justice because social
justice is not just公正的.
Justice is getting what you deserve应得，配得 without
favor. Social justice is getting what you
don’t deserve because you are favored受到优待的.
Justice is blind. Social justice is not.
Let's say a man robs a store. Justice demands
but one thing: that he be tried审判 in a court
of justice, and, if he is found guilty, punished.
That is not how social justice works. Social
justice doesn’t only ask if the person is
guilty. It asks about his economic condition:
Is he poor or wealthy? About his upbringing养育，抚养:
What kind of childhood did he have? About
his race or ethnicity: Is he a member of a
group that has been historically oppressed压迫，折磨?
Justice demands that everyone be equal under
the law. Social justice demands that everyone
be equal. Period. Economically, socially,
and in every other possible way.
Justice asks, “Who did it?” Social justice
asks, “Why did he do it?”
Lost in all these social justice considerations
is the individual’s own responsibility for
what he did. That’s why social justice advocates拥护者
have abandoned the term “justice.” They
deem认为 justice alone as unfair. And sometimes
it is. A man who was beaten by his father
and abandoned by his mother is more likely
to commit犯下 a violent crime than a man raised
in a loving home. But those facts cannot and
should not determine判定 his innocence or guilt.
Why? Because justice is, first and foremost最先的，最重要的,
about truth: Is the person guilty or innocent
of the crime? None of us is omniscient无所不知的. We
don’t know why people do what they do. After
all, the vast大量的 majority of people raised in
abusive homes do not commit violent crimes.
Nor do the vast majority of people who are
members of an historically oppressed group.
Being a victim, however that is defined, is
no excuse for hurting other people. And what
about those who are hurt—the victims of
those crimes? Shouldn’t they, and other
law-abiding守法的 citizens公民, be society’s first
consideration?
Social justice advocates say no. They say
we need social justice to even things out.
And that means favoring偏袒，有利于 the have-nots贫民 over
the haves—the poor over the rich, the female
over the male, and the brown or black over
the white.
The Bible does not see the world this way.
In fact, it speaks against it in very explicit明确的，清楚的
terms.
Here’s a law in the Book of Exodus出埃及记: “Do
not pervert歪曲，颠倒 justice by siding with站在...一边 the crowd,
and do not show favoritism偏袒 to a poor person
in a lawsuit.”
Here’s one in Leviticus利未记: “Do not pervert
justice; do not show partiality偏心 to the poor
or favoritism to the great but judge your
neighbor justly.”
Moses, the greatest lawgiver in history, declares
in Deuteronomy申命记: “Follow justice and justice
alone.”
And the New Testament约 declares in the Book
of Romans: “God shows no partiality.”
None of this means that there is no place
for compassion in a system of justice. Of
course, there is. The Bible is preoccupied全神贯注的
with the protection of the widow, the orphan,
and unfortunate不幸的. But compassion follows justice.
It doesn’t precede it.
Also, justice, in and of itself, is compassionate.
First, to the victims受害者 of crime and to their
loved ones. And second, to the criminal: How
can you become a better human being if you
don’t first recognize that you’ve done
something wrong?
That’s why any time we put an adjective形容词
before the word “justice,” we no longer
have justice. Economic justice, racial justice,
environmental justice—any form of “social”
justice which seeks to “correct” actual
justice—undermines破坏，暗中破坏 justice.
So, then, if social justice is not a biblical
concept, why do so many churches and synagogues犹太教会堂
promote it?
Because many Christians and Jews no longer
regard biblical principles as binding有约束力的. Because
it’s a lot easier to dispense分发 compassion同情，怜悯
than hold people to a biblical standard. And
because leftism has superseded取代 the Bible in
many houses of worship—and leftism, as a
guiding principle, holds that the weak are
good and the powerful are bad.
That’s why the great battle of our time
is between Judeo-Christian犹太教与基督教 values and leftist
values. The former is rooted in justice; the
latter is not.
I’m Allie Beth Stuckey, host of Relatable
on BlazeTV, for Prager University.